Guide to the James H. Laue papers, 1936-1999
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: Conflict Resolution Papers, 1967-1993
  - Conflict Clinic, Inc. - Resolving Development Disputes: A Workshop on Negotiation and Joint Problem-Solving Tools for Those Concerned about Land Development Disputes in Northern Virginia, October 13, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Conflict Clinic, Inc. - Selected Bibliography: Conflict Resolution and Its Applications, ca. 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Conflict Clinic, Inc. - Short Term Public Involvement: A Workshop for Fairfax County Employees, Spring and Fall 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Conflict Clinic, Inc. - Tom Stoner, Chairman of the Board, Announces the Appointment of James H. Laueas President and Executive Director The Conflict Clinic, Inc., June 1, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    printed announcement on 3x5" cardstock
  - Conflict Clinic, Inc. - Workshop Materials, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Conflict Intervention" by James Laue, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    reprinted from the Handbook of Applied Sociology, pp. 67-90
  - Conflict Management Book - Contents and Chapters 1-2, ca. 1984 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conflict Management Book Proposal, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Conflict Resolution" (Box 9, Folder 12)
    trainer manual by Elizabeth Rose and Angela Callahan
  - "Conflict Resolution: A Challenge for the Church", August 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    by James Laue, copied from Engage/Social Action Forum 43
  - Conflict Resolution Center, Inc. - Conflict Resolution Notes, 1983-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - "Introduction", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 1: "The Concept of Conflict: History and Development", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    by Hugh Boeving
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 3: "The Field of Conflict Resolution Emerges", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    by George Shaner
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 4: "Toward a Comprehensive Theory of Conflict Resolution: Human Needs and Social Order", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    by Jonathan Brooks
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 5: "The First Skill: Assessing the Data and Dynamics of a Conflict", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    by Diane LeResche
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 6: "Selecting Intervention Goals, Strategies and Processes", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    by Donald Bassett
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 7: "Designing and Applying the Process", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    by Susan Shearouse
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 8: "The Third Party", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    by Robert K. Reed
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 9: "Becoming a Peacemaker: Integrating Self, Theory and Practice", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    by Peter J. Bryan Swanson
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 10: "A Foundation for Ethical Behavior", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    by Frank Dukes
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 11: "Contemporary Ethical Issues in Third Party Intervention", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    by Brian Polkinghorn
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter 12: "Serving Human Needs: Some Lessons and Guidelines", ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Conflict Resolution Handbook - Chapter References, ca. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Conflict Resolution - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Brochures, 1980-1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Centre for Intergroup Studies, Southern Regional Council, etc.
  - "Conflict Resolution Skills: A Trainer's Manual", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    prepared by Lonnie Weiss for the Illinois Coalition Against Domestic Violence
  - Congressional Records - Alternative Dispute Resolution, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Records - Education Amendments, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Coping with Conflict: North Central Regional Workshop, May 16-19, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Zion, Illinois
  - Coping with Conflict: Strategies for Extension Community Development and Public Policy Professionals, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Coping with Conflict: Strategies for Extension Community Development and Public Policy Professionals, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    duplicates
  - Corp Group International Mediation Project, October 15, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Creative Approaches to Resolution of Conflict in Public Issues: Tobacco", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    The Carter Center, Emory University
  - "The Creative, Peaceful Class of Conflict Management Approaches", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    by Richard Fogg
  - Crime and Delinquency, April 1980 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    journal
  - Danforth Foundation - St. Louis Leadership Program, 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "The Development of Community Conflict Intervention", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Dictionary of International Biography, Winter 1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    invitation soliciting biographical information from Laue at the recommendation of J. R. L. Feilleux
  - "The Dilemmas of Mediation Practice: A Study of Ethical Dilemma and Policy Implications", 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    report by Robert A. Baruch Bush for the National Institute for Dispute Resolution (NIDR)
  - Disney / Libby, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    notes and proposal for "imagineered" pavilion of conflict resolution at Epcot
  - Dispute Resolution FORUM, Journal of the National Institute for Dispute Resolution (NIDR), 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Do As I Say: A Review Essay of John W. Burton, Resolving Deep-Rooted Conflict: A Handbook", 1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    by John N. Warfield
  - Earth Day, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Economic Development Conflicts, November 1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Engage/Social Action, May 1973, January 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    "The Siege at Wounded Knee" and "Violence and Nonviolence in the Struggle for Social Justice"
  - Environmental Mediation International, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    notes and papers on environmental law, the Union Carbide disaster in Bhopal, India, and the settlement of AIDS disputes
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) - Negotiated Rulemaking, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - EPCOT: An Introduction, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Escalative Intervention in Small-Group Conflict, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "The Ethics of Intervention in Community Disputes", 1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    by James Laue and Gerald W. Cormick
  - The Ethics of Social Intervention: Community Crisis Intervention Programs, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    edited by James Laue and Gerald W. Cormick
  - The Ethics of Social Intervention: Community Crisis Intervention Programs, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    duplicate
  - Evaluation of LEAA Grant No. 76-ED-99-0001, October 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Center for Correctional Justice, Washington, DC: "Development of Inmate Grievance Procedures" - quarterly reports by John R. Hepburn, project director, and James Laue, principal investigator
  - Executive Seminar on Alternative Dispute Resolution Procedures, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    US Army Corps of Engineers
  - Farm Debt Mediation: Background Information, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "Farm Finance Mediation", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    by Stephen Erickson and Marilyn McKnight
  - Farmer-Lender Mediation Program, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Minnesota State Planning Agency
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service: 43rd Annual Report, Fiscal Year 1990, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Fellowship, October/November 1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    magazine of the Fellowship on Reconciliation; cover features Palestinian demonstration in the West Bank
  - "The Field of Conflict Resolution: Cooptation or Social Change?", 1981 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Final Report of the Bethel College Project Supported by the Fund for the Improvement of Post-Secondary Education, 1974-1977, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ford Foundation Consultation Policy, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Harvard Medical School's Laboratory of Community Psychiatry designation of Laue as Ford Foundation consultant
  - Ford Foundation Evaluation - National Center for Dispute Settlement (NCDS) and Racial Negotiations Project (RNP), part 1 of 2, Summer 1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ford Foundation Evaluation - NCDS and RNP, part 2 of 2, Summer 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation - First Monitoring Report for Grants, June 30, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation Grants, 1971-1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Formal Mediation in Intergovernmental Disputes: Municipal Annexation Negotiations in Virginia, July/August 1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    by Roger Richman, copied from Public Administration Review
  - Fort Worth I-30 Expansion Dispute, Summer 1986 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Fort Worth, part 1 of 2, December 17, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Fort Worth, part 2 of 2, December 17, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Fort Worth - Active, October 1986 - February 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Fostering Development in Metropolitan St. Louis", December 1982 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    report submitted to John W. Hanley, Chairman of the City-County Task Force of Civic Progress, by Dana L. Spitzer, Regional Government Affairs Director, Monsanto Company
  - Foundation News: The Magazine of Philanthropy, May/June 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "The Future of Community Conflict Intervention", Summer 1982 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    by James Laue, copied from the Journal of Intergroup Relations
  - Gephardt/Hawley Farm Debt Mediation Title, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    notes
  - "Getting to the Table", 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Getting to the Table: A Guide for Senior Managers", October 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    by William Potapchuck, James Laue, and John S. Murray; US Army Corps of Engineers Working Paper No. 3, Alternative Dispute Resolution Series
  - Glossary - Conflict Resolution Book, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Grace United Methodist Church Newsletter, December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Grant Proposal, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    World Policy Institute
  - Guide to Situation Assessment / Guide to Conflict Assessment, ca. 1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Holiday Inn, Alexandria, October 1985 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    report and correspondence on lost personal items
  - I-30 Working Group - Fort Worth, Texas, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - I-30 Working Group - Fort Worth, Texas, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Iliff School of Theology, January 25-28, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Improved Quality of City Life through the Transcendental Meditation Program: Decreased Crime Rate", July 1976 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    by Candace Borland and Garland Landrith III
  - "In Defense of Creation: The Nuclear Crisis and a Just Peace", 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    The United Methodist Council of Bishops
  - "Individual Experience and Critical Consciousness: Sources of Social Change in Everyday Life", undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Inflation Forum, Roos/Gephardt, October 13, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    notes, news clippings, and memoranda
  - Institute for Community Economics - Revolving Loan Fund, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution (IMCR) - Interim Report to the Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    CMCR and BMCD monitoring
  - Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution (IMCR) - Monitoring Report to the Ford Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Institute for Servant Leadership, part 1 of 2, ca. 1978-1983 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Institute for Servant Leadership, part 2 of 2, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Intergroup Education Bibliography - National Conference on Christians and Jews, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - International Conflict and Nuclear Power, 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - International Mediation: A Working Guide, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    a Harvard Negotiation Project publication
  - International Mediation - Arab-Israeli Conflict, 1985-1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    articles and memoranda
  - International Mediation - Northern Ireland, Europe, Faulkland Islands, 1980-1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Iowa Peace Institute, March-September 1991 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    newsletter, notes, articles
  - Iowa Peace Institute - Seminar on Conflict Resolution for Soviet Delegation and Iowa Hosts, August 20, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    coordinated by James Laue
  - Iowa Peace Institute - Tibet / John McDonald, Ambassador, part 1 of 2, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Iowa Peace Institute - Tibet / John McDonald, Ambassador, part 2 of 2, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Iowa Peace Institute - Vision Workshop, November 8, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Iowa Memorial Union
  - Iowa Religious Leaders, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Ecumenical Ministries of Iowa; includes notes and correspondence
  - Iran Hostages, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Iran Hostages - Bill Blakemore, ABC News, 1980-1985 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "Ireland and Northern Ireland: Review of a Visit", June 1986 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - James McCarthy, Director of the Center for Mediation in Higher Education, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    memoranda, project description, and progress report
  - Jehovah's Witnesses - Watchtower and Awake!, May 1960 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    journals
  - Jimmy Carter, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    speech quotes, press releases, and news clippings
  - John Dellenback, President of the Christian College Consortium, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Journal of Intergroup Relations, November 1975; Summer 1981 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    issues include article and book review by Laue
  - Journal of Intergroup Relations, Summer 1982 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    James Laue, special issue editor and contributor
  - Journal of Urban Affairs, Vol. 5 No. 1, Winter 1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Symposium on the Urban Impacts of Reagan Administration Policies
  - Kanawa County Schools Textbook Advisory Committee, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    report on review and vote on series of textbooks; Charleston, West Virginia
  - Kent State, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    press releases and memoranda from Reverend John P. Adams and James Laue
  - Kent State, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    articles, press releases, and correspondence on Justice Department reopening inquiry into Kent State shooting
  - Kent State, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    statement of parents and families of students killed or wounded; correspondence between Kent State trustees and university president, Brage Golding; correspondence re: registration of Kent State shootings location as historic preservation site
  - Kent State, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    notes and memos on meetings with Kent State trustees, administrative representatives, and congressmen
  - Kent State, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Kent State Weekly (newsletter) and the Daily Kent Stater (newspaper); Kent State FACT (First Amendment Conservation Task-Force), Vol. 1 No. 2; memoranda from William Keeney of the Consortium on Peace Research, Education and Development (COPRED)
  - "Kent State and May 4th: A Social Science Perspective", 1978 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    by Thomas R. hensley and Jerry M. Lewis, 176 pages
  - Kent State Meeting, July 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Kent State Meeting and Notes, July 1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Kent State - Proposed Act to Preserve the Site of the Kent State Shootings, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Kentucky Welfare Rights Handbook, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Kettering Foundation - "Getting to the Table" Conference, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Kettering Foundation - Negotiated Investment Strategy (NIS), 1981-1984 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Kettering Review, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - KWMU Radio, University of Missouri, St. Louis [NPR] - "The Subject is Peacemaking", February 1987 - June 1987 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Lawyers and Judges - The Essential Humanists in a Technological Society", 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    by Frank M. Coffin
  - Leadership St. Louis Program - Alumni Training, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Learning to Wage Peace", ca. 1981 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Living the Kingdom: Faith and Politics in the Northern Ireland Conflict", 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    published by An Interchurch Group on Faith and Politics, 138 pages; includes notes for a sermon on peace
  - "Local Dispute Resolution: Its Relevance for International Negotiation", July 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    by James Laue, 54 pages
  - "Mandated Participation and Settlement Coercion: Dispute Resolution as it Relates to the Courts", January 5, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    report from the Society of Professionals in Dispute Resolution (SPIDR)
  - "Mediating Urban Policy: A New Approach to Meeting the Needs of American Cities", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    an analysis of the negotiated investment strategy (NIS) by James Laue, 16 pages
  - Mediation: The Newsletter of FIRM, summer 1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Forum for Initiatives in Reparation and Mediation
  - "Mediation in an Annexation Dispute", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    by Roger Richman
  - "Mediation Primer: A Training Guide for Mediators in the Criminal Justice System", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    by Dean E. Peachey, Brian Snyder, and Alan Teichroeb for Community Justice Initiatives of Waterloo Region
  - Mediation Quarterly - Editor's Notes and Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum Re: Comparative Law in Japan and China, March 29, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Faculty Dispute Resolution Seminar
  - Mennonite Conciliation Service Consultations, 1977-1978, 1986, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Rev. John P. Adams
  - Mennonite Conciliation Service Mediation Training Manual, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Meramec River Dam Dispute, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    St. Louis
  - Meramec River Recreation Association, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Miami Convention Intervention Workshop, October 28-29, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Washington, DC
  - Miami Interaction: A Publication of Continuing Education / Urban Affairs Project / University of Miami / Coral Gables, Florida, June 1969 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Miami Recession, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Articles on Conflict Resolution, 1971-1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Articles on Conflict Resolution, 1977-1987 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Articles on Conflict Resolution, 1982-1993 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles on Conflict Resolution and Peacemaking, 1965-1993 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on Conflict Resolution and Peacemaking, 1970-1989 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Mississippi Negotiated Investment Strategy (NIS), December 1984 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Missouri Basin States Association, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Missouri Basin States Association Billings, November 12-13, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Missouri Farms, Fall 1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Conflict Clinic, Inc.
  - Mitigation of Litigation, June 19, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "Model" Siting Negotiation Processes, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    hazardous waste management planning
  - Music and Religion in Public Schools, part 1 of 3, 1979-1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Music and Religion in Public Schools, part 2 of 3, 1979-1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Music and Religion in Public Schools, part 3 of 3, 1979-1981 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "The Myth of Mediation Neutrality", 1986 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    by Marlene Maskornick; rough draft with notes
  - National Association for Community Justice, October 1986 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement, part 1 of 3, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    American Arbitration Association; newsletters, brochures, memoranda
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement, part 2 of 3, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    report on Massachusetts Correctional Institution at Walpole; class exercises and training materials
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement, part 3 of 3, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    program development; news clippings; consultation materials - "The Processarians"; speech by Jery Wurf, President of the AFSCME; correspondence with Gerald W. Cormick, Director of the Community Crisis Intervention Center
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement - Carbon NCDS and RNP Evaluation for Ford Foundation Grant, September 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement Monitoring Report, Ford Foundation, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - National Center for Dispute Settlement - National Institute of Mental Health Campus Unrest Proposal, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - National Institute for Dispute Resolution - "Program on Professional Education: Grants Announcement and Progress Report", September 1987 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - National Institute for Dispute Resolution - Progress Report and Reports 2-4, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    includes letter informing Laue of National Conference on Peacemaking and Conflict Resolution sponsored by NIDR and the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation
  - Nebraska - Disputes Between Farmers and Lenders, Fall 1986 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    article and notes
  - Negotiated Investment Strategy (NIS) Agreement, July 1979 - June 1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    notes and memoranda; Gary, Indiana
  - Negotiated Investment Strategy (NIS) Agreement, July - December 1980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "A Negotiated Investment Strategy: The City of Gary, Indiana", December 10, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    report with documents prepared by teams representing the City of Gary, the State of Indiana, and the Region V (Chicago) Office of the Federal Regional Council, United States Government
  - Negotiated Investment Strategy - Mediating Urban Policy, 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Negotiated Investment Strategy Notes, Fall 1982 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Negotiated Investment Strategy - Status of the Agreement After the First Year, December 21, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Neighborhood Conflict Resolution, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    misc. brochures and newsletters
  - Neighborhood Development, January 3, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    James Laue and Elliot Stein, Jr.
  - Neighborhood Justice Center - Kansas City, Missouri, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    contains memoranda and meeting minutes; Maurice Macey, director
  - Neighborhood Resources Center Manual, ca. 1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    University of Missouri, St. Louis
  - North-Central Regional Series on Community Development and Human Relations, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Nos. 36-1, 36-2, 36-4, 36-8, 36-9, and 36-11
  - Northern Ireland Visitors, March 1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Conflict Resolution, 1986-1988 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Crisis and the Pursuit of Peace, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    United Methodist Council of Bishops
  - Oaklawn Center, 1967-1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    correspondence and brochure; community crisis intervention; Harvard Medical School
  - "Out of Court: A Simulation of Mediation", 1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    mediation training packet by Ethan Katsh and Janet Rifkin
  - "Overcoming Cultural Impediments to Human Survival", 1977 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    by David G. Gil
  - Partners for Democratic Change, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Partnership Forum for Children and Family Services - Full Meeting: Agenda Setting, July 25 and August 9, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    Massachusetts Department of Social Services (DSS); Larry Susskind
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Correspondence to Mediation Staff, Summer and Fall 1984 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Lawrence Susskind, Maurice Boisvert, Sylvia Watts, Daniel Donahue
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Drafts: Sections of Agreement, December 1984 - January 1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Massachusetts DSS; Public Private Partnership Program (PPPP); NIS; Lawrence Susskind; Wendy Fishbeck; Inter-University Consortium to Improve the Theory and Practice of Dispute Resolution
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Final Agreement Drafts and Executive Summary, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)